Register of the Gleb Struve Papers 1810-1985
Hoover Institution Archives
Gleb Struve papers
1810-1985
85018
Struve, Gleb
156 manuscript boxes, 26 card file boxes, 5 oversize boxes, 10 envelopes, 5 microfilm reels, 7 phonotapes, memorabilia (77 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, speeches and writings, printed matter, and audio-visual material, relating to Russian literature and culture both in the Soviet Union and the emigration, political conditions in the Soviet Union, Soviet dissidents, and the Russian emigre community. Includes correspondence and writings of Nikolai Gumilev, Marina Tsvetaeva and other Russian writers. Available on microfilm (265 reels). Digital copies of selected items also available.
Administrative Information
Access
Closed. Microfilm use copies available.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1985.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (265 reels).
Access Points
Russian literature.; Russia--Civilization.; Soviet Union--Politics and government.; Dissenters--Soviet Union.; Russians in foreign countries.; Russia.; Soviet Union.; Drawings.; Phonotapes.; Gumilev, N. (Nikolai), 1886-1921.; TSetaeva, Marina, 1892-1941.
Biographical Note
1898, April 19 Born, St. Petersburg, Russia. Son of Petr Berngardovich Struve
1917-1918 Serves in the Volunteer (White) Army. Spends three months as hostage in the Novorossiisk city prison
1918 Escapes to Finland and later emigrates to England
1921 B.A., Balliol College, Oxford
1921-1932 Engages in journalism in Germany and then France. Contributes mainly to Russian emigre newspapers in Paris including Vozrozhdenie, Rossiia and Rossiia i Slavianstvo
1932-1946 Lecturer and later Reader in Russian Literature, University of London
1933 Translator, Ivan Bunin, The Well of Days
1935 Author, Soviet Russian Literature. Revised and enlarged editions appear under somewhat different titles in 1944, 1951 and 1971. Translated into French, 1946; German, 1958 and 1964; Italian, 1975
1946 Author (with E.A. Moore), Practical Russian
1946-1947 Visiting Lecturer, University of California, Berkeley
1947-1967 Professor of Slavic Languages and Literatures, University of California, Berkeley
1950 Author, Russkii evropeets: materialy dlia biografii i kharakteristiki kniazia P.B. Kozlovskogo Translator (with Mary Kriger), George Orwell's Animal Farm. Reissued in 1967 and 1971
1952 Editor (with G. A. Birkett), Anton Chekhov, Selected Short Stories Editor, Neizdannyi Gumilev: "Otravlennaia tunika" i drugie neizdannye proizvedeniia
1956 Author, Russkaia literatura v izgnanii: opyt istoricheskogo obzora russkoi zarubezhnoi literatury. Second edition, 1984
1957 Author, Geschichte der Sowjetliteratur
1961 Editor and translator, Russian Stories Editor, Boris Pasternak, Sochineniia
1962-1968 Editor, N. Gumilev, Sobranie sochinenii
1964 Editor, Osip Mandel'shtam. Sobranie sochinenii v dvukh tomakh. Second edition, 1981
1965 Editor, Anna Akhmatova, Sochineniia. Second edition, 1967 Editor, Nikolai Zabolotskii, Stikhotvoreniia
1967 Author, A Century of Russian Prose and Verse Author, Utloe zhil'e: Izbrannye stikhi 1915-1949. Second edition, 1978
1969 Editor, Anna Akhmatova, Rekviem Editor, Nikolai Kliuev, Sochineniia
1971 Hon. LLD., University of Toronto
1972 Editor, Marina Tsvetaeva, Neizdannye pis'ma
1978 Recipient, Berkeley Citation
1979 Author, K istorii russkoi poezii 1910kh--nachala 1920kh godov
1981 Author, O chetyrekh poetakh
1982 Editor, Maksimilian Voloshin, Stikhotvoreniia i poemy v dvukh tomakh
1985, June 4 Dies, Berkeley, California
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, speeches and writings, printed matter, and audio-visual material, relating to Russian literature and culture both in the Soviet Union and the emigration, political conditions in the Soviet Union, Soviet dissidents, and the Russian emigre community. Includes correspondence and writings of Nikolai Gumilev, Marina Tsvetaeva and other Russian writers. Also available on microfilm (265 reels).
Container List
- Additional Guides
  Downloadable PDF file of the Microfilm Reel Content Guide
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1924-1985 (Boxes 1-4)
  Biographical material, including personal documents, papers relating to his family and clippings. Arranged by subject.
  - Official documents, 1924-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Struve family. Miscellaneous material, including family tree, correspondence re family history and printed matter, 1939-1985 (Folder 2-3)
  - Autobiographical letter re childhood, typescript, 1976 (Folder 4)
  - Vyborgskoe Kommercheskoe Uchilishche. Includes correspondence and questionnaires, typescript copies, 1955-1978 (Folder 5)
  - Balliol College, Oxford, miscellaneous material, 1960-1962 (Folder 6)
  - University of London, correspondence and official documents, 1932-1957 (Folder 7)
  - University of California, Berkeley
    - Correspondence
      - 1946-1952 (Folder 8)
      - 1953-1958 (Folder 9)
      - 1959-1963 (Folder 10)
      - 1964-1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 1970-1985 (Folder 2)
    - Annual Supplement to Bio-Bibliography, University of California, Berkeley, printed copies, 1953-1965 (Folder 3)
  - Soviet exchange students and visitors, 1959-1965 (Folder 4)
  - Applications for grants
    - Fellowship Application Forms, John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1955 and 1963 (Folder 5)
    - N.E.H. Grant, 1966 (Folder 6)
  - Professional honors
    - Honorary Degree, University of Toronto, miscellaneous material, 1971 (Folder 7)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies, Award for Distinguished Contributions to Slavic Studies, 1973 (Folder 8)
    - Berkeley Citation, 1978 (Folder 9)
  - Memberships in professional organizations and other societies, 1948-1978 (Folder 10)
  - Anniversary celebration greetings
    - 75th birthday, 1973 (Folder 11)
    - 80th birthday, 1978 (Folder 12)
  - Biographical articles and announcements of awards in periodical press. Vitas and questionnaires, 1937-1983 (Folder 13)
  - Obituaries, typescript and printed copies, 1985 (Folder 14)
  - Letters of condolence, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Public lectures. Announcements, 1933-1973 (Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous reviews of his work, 1929-1969 (Folder 3)
  - Reports to publishers, typescript drafts, n.d. (Folder 4)
  - Articles and letters to the editor re Gleb Struve, 1949-1977 (Folder 5)
  - Soviet press re Gleb Struve. Clippings and typescript excerpts, 1953-1973 (Folder 6-8)
  - Bibliographies
    - Gleb Struve's writings, typescript copies, n.d. (Folder 9)
    - Emigre literature in his library (Folder 10)
  - Correspondents. Records of letters received and sent, 1958-1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Lists of persons to receive complementary copies of his printed work, n.d. (Folder 2)
- CORRESPONDENCE, CHRONOLOGICAL, 1922-1985 (Boxes 5-23, 183)
  Personal correspondence of Gleb Struve, arranged chronologically.
  - Undated (Box 4, Folder 3-6)
  - 1922-1923 (Folder 7)
  - 1924 (Folder 8)
  - 1925 (Folder 9)
  - 1926 (Folder 10)
  - 1927 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1928 (Folder 2)
  - 1929 (Folder 3)
  - 1930 (Folder 4)
  - 1931 (Folder 5)
  - 1932 (Folder 6)
  - 1933 (Folder 7)
  - 1934 (Folder 8)
  - 1935 (Folder 9)
  - 1936 (Folder 10)
  - 1937 (Folder 11)
  - 1938 (Folder 12)
  - 1939 (Folder 13)
  - 1940 (Folder 14)
  - 1941 (Folder 15)
  - 1942 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1943 (Folder 2)
  - 1944 (Folder 3)
  - 1945 (Folder 4)
  - 1946
    - A-P (Folder 5)
    - R-Z (Folder 6)
  - 1947
    - A-M (Folder 7)
    - N-Z (Folder 8)
  - 1948
    - A (Folder 9)
    - B (Folder 10)
    - C-F (Folder 11)
    - G-K (Folder 12)
    - L (Folder 13)
    - M (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - N-P (Folder 2)
    - R-S (Folder 3)
    - T (Folder 4)
    - U-V (Folder 5)
    - W-Z (Folder 6)
  - 1949
    - A (Folder 7)
    - B (Folder 8)
    - C (Folder 9)
    - D-G (Folder 10)
    - H-J (Folder 11)
    - K-L (Folder 12)
    - M-P (Folder 13)
    - R (Folder 14)
    - S (Folder 15)
    - T-U (Folder 16)
    - V-Z (Folder 17)
  - 1950
    - A (Folder 18)
    - B-C (Folder 19)
    - D-G (Folder 20)
    - H-J (Folder 21)
    - K-L (Folder 22)
    - M (Folder 23)
    - N (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - P (Folder 2)
    - R (Folder 3)
    - S-T (Folder 4)
    - V-Z (Folder 5)
  - 1951
    - A-B (Folder 6)
    - C-D (Folder 7)
    - E-I (Folder 8)
    - K-L (Folder 9)
    - M-P (Folder 10)
    - R-S (Folder 11)
    - U-W (Folder 12)
    - X-Z (Folder 13)
  - 1952
    - A (Folder 14)
    - B (Folder 15)
    - C-E (Folder 16)
    - F-I (Folder 17)
    - K-L (Folder 18)
    - M-P (Folder 19)
    - R (Folder 20)
    - S-U (Folder 21)
    - V-Z (Folder 22)
  - 1953
    - A (Folder 23)
    - B (Folder 24)
    - C-D (Folder 25)
    - E-F (Folder 26)
    - G-J (Folder 27)
    - K-L (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - M-N (Folder 2)
    - O-P (Folder 3)
    - R (Folder 4)
    - S-T (Folder 5)
    - U-V (Folder 6)
    - W-Z (Folder 7)
  - 1954
    - A (Folder 8)
    - B-D (Folder 9)
    - E-F (Folder 10)
    - G-J (Folder 11)
    - K-N (Folder 12)
    - P (Folder 13)
    - Q-S (Folder 14)
    - T-V (Folder 15)
    - W-Z (Folder 16)
  - 1955
    - A-B (Folder 17)
    - C-D (Folder 18)
    - E-F (Folder 19)
    - G-H (Folder 20)
    - K-L (Folder 21)
    - M-N (Folder 22)
    - P-S (Folder 23)
    - T-Z (Folder 24)
  - 1956
    - A-B (Folder 25)
    - C-F (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - G-J (Folder 2)
    - K-L (Folder 3)
    - M-O (Folder 4)
    - P (Folder 5)
    - R-S (Folder 6)
    - T-V (Folder 7)
    - W-Z (Folder 8)
  - 1957
    - A-B (Folder 9)
    - C-F (Folder 10)
    - G-I (Folder 11)
    - J-L (Folder 12)
    - M (Folder 13)
    - N-O (Folder 14)
    - P (Folder 15)
    - R-S (Folder 16)
    - T-Z (Folder 17)
  - 1958
    - A-D (Folder 18)
    - E-F (Folder 19)
    - G (Folder 20)
    - H-J (Folder 21)
    - K-L (Folder 22)
    - M (Folder 23)
    - N-O (Folder 24)
    - P (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - R (Folder 2)
    - S (Folder 3)
    - T (Folder 4)
    - U-V (Folder 5)
    - W-Z (Folder 6)
  - 1959
    - A-B (Folder 7)
    - C-D (Folder 8)
    - E-G (Folder 9)
    - H-J (Folder 10)
    - K-L (Folder 11)
    - M-N (Folder 12)
    - O-P (Folder 13)
    - R-S (Folder 14)
    - T-Z (Folder 15)
  - 1960
    - A-B (Folder 16)
    - C-D (Folder 17)
    - E-H (Folder 18)
    - I-L (Folder 20)
    - M-N (Folder 21)
    - O-P (Folder 22)
    - R-S (Folder 23)
    - T (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - U-V (Folder 2)
    - W-Z (Folder 3)
  - 1961
    - A-B (Folder 4)
    - C-F (Folder 5)
    - G-H (Folder 6)
    - I-J (Folder 7)
    - K-L (Folder 8)
    - M-N (Folder 9)
    - O-P (Folder 10)
    - R-S (Folder 11)
    - T (Folder 12)
    - U-V (Folder 13)
    - W-Z (Folder 14)
  - 1962
    - A-B (Folder 15)
    - C-D (Folder 16)
    - E-F (Folder 17)
    - G-K (Folder 18)
    - L-M (Folder 19)
    - N-P (Folder 20)
    - R-S (Folder 21)
    - T-U (Folder 22)
    - V-Z (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1963
    - A-B (Folder 2)
    - C-F (Folder 3)
    - G-L (Folder 4)
    - M-O (Folder 5)
    - P-R (Folder 6)
    - S (Folder 7)
    - T-U (Folder 8)
    - V-Z (Folder 9)
  - 1964
    - A-B (Folder 10)
    - C-F (Folder 11)
    - G-J (Folder 12)
    - K-O (Folder 13)
    - P-R (Folder 14)
    - S (Folder 15)
    - T (Folder 16)
    - U-Z (Folder 17)
  - 1965
    - A-B (Folder 18)
    - C-D (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - E-J (Folder 2)
    - K-L (Folder 3)
    - M-R (Folder 4)
    - S-T (Folder 5)
    - U-V (Folder 6)
    - W-Z (Folder 7)
  - 1966
    - A-B (Folder 8)
    - C-D (Folder 9)
    - E-F (Folder 10)
    - G-J (Folder 11)
    - K-L (Folder 12)
    - M-N (Folder 13)
    - O-P (Folder 14)
    - R-S (Folder 15)
    - T-U (Folder 16)
    - V-Z (Folder 17)
  - 1967
    - A-B (Folder 18)
    - C-D (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - E-H (Folder 2)
    - K-L (Folder 3)
    - M-N (Folder 4)
    - O-P (Folder 5)
    - R-S (Folder 6)
    - T-U (Folder 7)
    - V-Z (Folder 8)
  - 1968
    - A-B (Folder 9)
    - C-F (Folder 10)
    - G-H (Folder 11)
    - I-J (Folder 12)
    - K-L (Folder 13)
    - M-N (Folder 14)
    - O-P (Folder 15)
    - R (Folder 16)
    - S (Folder 17)
    - U (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - W-Z (Folder 2)
  - 1969
    - A-B (Folder 3)
    - C-D (Folder 4)
    - E-F (Folder 5)
    - G-H (Folder 6)
    - I-K (Folder 7)
    - L-M (Folder 8)
    - N-P (Folder 9)
    - Q-R (Folder 10)
    - S-T (Folder 11)
    - U-Z (Folder 12)
  - 1970
    - A-B (Folder 13)
    - C-D (Folder 14)
    - E-F (Folder 15)
    - G-H (Folder 16)
    - I-K (Folder 17)
    - L-M (Folder 18)
    - N-P (Folder 19)
    - R-S (Folder 20)
    - T-U (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - V-Z (Folder 2)
  - 1971
    - A-D (Folder 3)
    - E-G (Folder 4)
    - H-J (Folder 5)
    - K-L (Folder 6)
    - M-N (Folder 7)
    - O-P (Folder 8)
    - Q-R (Folder 9)
    - S-T (Folder 10)
    - U-Z (Folder 11)
  - 1972
    - A-D (Folder 12)
    - E-F (Folder 13)
    - G-H (Folder 14)
    - I-K (Folder 15)
    - L-M (Folder 16)
    - N-P (Folder 17)
    - R-S (Folder 18)
    - T-V (Folder 19)
    - W-Z (Folder 20)
  - 1973
    - A-B (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - C-F (Folder 2)
    - G (Folder 3)
    - H-J (Folder 4)
    - K (Folder 5)
    - L-M (Folder 6)
    - N-P (Folder 7)
    - R (Folder 8)
    - S-T (Folder 9)
    - U-Z (Folder 10)
  - 1974
    - A-B (Folder 11)
    - C-D (Folder 12)
    - E-F (Folder 13)
    - H-I (Folder 14)
    - J-L (Folder 15)
    - M-N (Folder 16)
    - O-R (Folder 17)
    - S-T (Folder 18)
    - U-Z (Folder 19)
  - 1975
    - A-B (Folder 20)
    - C-D (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - E-F (Folder 2)
    - G-I (Folder 3)
    - K (Folder 4)
    - L-M (Folder 5)
    - N-P (Folder 6)
    - Q-R (Folder 7)
    - S (Folder 8)
    - T-Z (Folder 9)
  - 1976
    - A-B (Folder 10)
    - C-E (Folder 11)
    - F-G (Folder 12)
    - H-I (Folder 13)
    - J-L (Folder 14)
    - M-N (Folder 15)
    - O-P (Folder 16)
    - Q-R (Folder 17)
    - S-T (Folder 18)
    - U-Z (Folder 19)
  - 1977
    - A-B (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - C-D (Folder 2)
    - E-F (Folder 3)
    - G-H (Folder 4)
    - I-K (Folder 5)
    - L-M (Folder 6)
    - N-O (Folder 7)
    - P-Q (Folder 8)
    - R-S (Folder 9)
    - T-Z (Folder 10)
  - 1978
    - A-B (Folder 11)
    - C-D (Folder 12)
    - E-F (Folder 13)
    - G-H (Folder 14)
    - I-J (Folder 15)
    - K (Folder 16)
    - L-M (Folder 17)
    - N-O (Folder 18)
    - P (Folder 19)
    - R (Folder 20)
    - S-T (Folder 21)
    - U (Folder 22)
    - V-Z (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - 1979
    - A-B (Folder 2)
    - C-D (Folder 3)
    - E-F (Folder 4)
    - G-H (Folder 5)
    - I-K (Folder 6)
    - L-M (Folder 7)
    - N-O (Folder 8)
    - P-R (Folder 9)
    - S-T (Folder 10)
    - U-W (Folder 11)
    - X-Z (Folder 12)
  - 1980
    - A-B (Folder 13)
    - C (Folder 14)
    - D-E (Folder 15)
    - F-G (Folder 16)
    - H-J (Folder 17)
    - K (Folder 18)
    - L-M (Folder 19)
    - N-P (Folder 20)
    - Q-S (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - T (Folder 2)
    - U-Z (Folder 3)
  - 1981
    - A-B (Folder 4)
    - C-D (Folder 5)
    - E-G (Folder 6)
    - H-J (Folder 7)
    - K-L (Folder 8)
    - M-N (Folder 9)
    - O-P (Folder 10)
    - Q-R (Folder 11)
    - S-T (Folder 12)
    - U-Z (Folder 13)
  - 1982
    - A-B (Folder 14)
    - C-F (Folder 15)
    - G-J (Folder 16)
    - K-N (Folder 17)
    - O-R (Folder 18)
    - S (Folder 19)
    - T-Z (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - 1983
    - A-K (Folder 2)
    - L-Z (Folder 3)
  - 1984
    - A-L (Folder 4)
    - M-Z (Folder 5)
  - 1985 (Folder 6)
- CORRESPONDENCE, ALPHABETICAL, 1923-1985 (Boxes 23-45, 184)
  Personal correspondence of Gleb Struve, arranged alphabetically. Also includes correspondence of other members of his family.
  - General
    - Publishers
      - Undated, 1923-1932 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - 1933-1939 (Folder 8)
      - 1940-1949 (Folder 9)
      - 1950-1955 (Folder 10)
      - 1956-1961 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - 1962-1965 (Folder 2)
      - 1966-1968 (Folder 3)
      - 1969-1972 (Folder 4)
      - 1973-1977 (Folder 5)
      - 1978-1982 (Folder 6)
  - Alekseev, G. A., 1949-1961 (Folder 7)
  - Altman, 1969-1970 (Folder 8)
  - American Committee for Cultural Freedom, 1954-1955 (Folder 9)
  - American Slavic and East European Review. See Slavic Review
  - Annenkov, Iurii, 1965-1967 (Folder 10)
  - Arielli, Evgenii, 1978-1980 (Folder 11)
  - Association International de Litterature Comparee, 1966 (Folder 12)
  - Aucouturier, Michel, 1967-1981 (Folder 13)
  - Avinov, Maria, 1949-1971 (Folder 14)
  - Bailey, James, 1966-1970 (Folder 15)
  - Bantam Books, Inc., 1960-1968 (Folder 16)
  - Bartlett, Carole, 1965-1970 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Belousov, Konstantin, 1966-1981 (Folder 2)
  - Berlin, Sir Isaiah, 1949-1981 (Folder 3)
  - Bernadskaia, Olga, 1937-1966 (Folder 4)
  - Biasutti, Dorothy, 1929-1931 (Folder 5)
  - Blackwood's, 1944-1945 (Folder 6)
  - Blake, Patricia
    - 1962-1971 (Folder 7)
    - 1972-1973 (Folder 8)
    - 1974
    - 1975-1982
  - Bogdanovich, Vladislav
    - 1933-1935 (Folder 11)
    - 1936-1954 (Folder 12)
  - Books Abroad, 1949-1972 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation, (B.B.C.), 1937-1964 (Folder 2)
  - Brown, Clarence
    - 1959-1966 (Folder 3)
    - 1965-1968 (Folder 4)
  - Bunina, Vera, 1954-1957 (Folder 5)
  - Chalsma, William, 1964-1968 (Folder 6)
  - Chambers' Encyclopedia
    - 1943-1960 (Folder 7)
    - 1961-1965 (Folder 8)
  - Chekhov Publishing House, 1951-1956 (Folder 9)
  - Chelishchev, Leonid, 1947-1950 (Folder 10)
  - Chertkov, Leonid, 1975-1982 (Folder 11)
  - Chernosvitov, Lev, 1939-1946 (Folder 12)
  - Chernosvitov, M. V., 1960-1970 (Folder 13)
  - Chinnov, Igor, 1951-1982 (Folder 14)
  - Collier Books and P. F. Collier and Son Corp., 1946-1962 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Comparative Literature, 1948-1953 (Folder 2)
  - Conquest, Robert, 1962-1967 (Folder 3)
  - Cournos, John, 1959-1965 (Folder 4)
  - Dol'berg, Aleksandr, 1962 (Folder 5)
  - Edward Arnold & Co., 1946-1947 (Folder 6)
  - Ehrlich, Victor, 1953-1968 (Folder 7)
  - Elenev, Nikolai, 1953-1967 (Folder 8)
  - Elton, Oliver, 1935-1939 (Folder 9)
  - Encounter, 1954-1963 (Folder 10)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1940-1962 (Folder 11)
  - Ermolaev, Herman
    - 1959-1963 (Folder 12)
    - 1964-1969 (Folder 13)
    - 1970-1973 (Folder 14)
    - 1974-1985 (Folder 15)
  - Ermolaeva, Tatiana, 1965-1983 (Folder 16)
  - Etkind, E. G., 1975-1980 (Folder 17)
  - Evreinova, Anna, 1964-1968, and Evreinov, Nikolai Nikolaevich, 1952 (Folder 18)
  - Feuer, Kathryn
    - 1958-1963 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - 1964-1967 (Folder 2)
    - 1968-1970 (Folder 3)
    - 1971-1974 (Folder 4)
    - 1975-1984 (Folder 5)
  - Feuer, Lewis, 1968-1984 (Folder 6)
  - Fleishman, Lazar, 1978-1985 (Folder 7)
  - Florovskii, Fr. Georgii, 1923-1975 (Folder 8)
  - Forgues, Pierre, 1965-1966 (Folder 9)
  - Frank, Simon, 1924-1950 (Folder 10)
  - Frank, Tatiana
    - 1930-1952 (Folder 11)
    - 1953-1956 (Folder 12)
    - 1957-1967 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - 1968-1979 (Folder 2)
  - Galton, Dorothy
    - 1932-1961 (Folder 3)
    - 1962-1984 (Folder 4)
  - Gefding, Vladimir, 1949-1979 (Folder 5)
  - Georgievskii, Ivan, 1941-1949 (Folder 6)
  - Gerald Duckworth & Co. Ltd., 1934-1945 (Folder 7)
  - Gerschenkron, Alexander, 1950-1975 (Folder 8)
  - Ginsburg, Mirra, 1967-1968 (Folder 9)
  - Glazberg, Valentin, 1926-1950 (Folder 10)
  - Gorodetzky, Natalia, 1962-1966 (Folder 11)
  - Goul, Roman. See Gul', Roman
  - Graham, Sheelagh, 1984-1985 (Folder 12)
  - Grani. See Possev Druckerei & Verlag
  - Grunman, Paula. Correspondence with granddaughter, Iulia Struve, 1923-1929 (Folder 13)
  - Grynberg, R. N., 1949-1965 (Folder 14)
  - Guenther, Johannes von, 1961-1970 (Folder 15)
  - Gul', Roman, 1948-1979 (Folder 16)
  - Haight, Amanda, 1956-1968 (Folder 17)
  - Hayward, Max
    - 1958-1965 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - 1966-1976 (Folder 2)
  - Helen & Kurt Wolff Books, Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, Inc., 1975. See also correspondence with Dimitrii Panin (Folder 3)
  - Herbert, Sidney, Earl of Pembroke, 1944-1970 (Folder 4)
  - Hill, Cecil
    - 1924-1975 (Folder 5)
    - 1976-1977 (Folder 6)
    - 1978-1980 (Folder 7)
    - 1982-1985 (Folder 8)
  - Hoeffding, Waldemar. See Gefding, Vladimir
  - Hogarth Press, 1932-1934. Includes letters from Leonard Wolff (Folder 9)
  - Hollingsworth, Barry, 1966-1975 (Folder 10)
  - Hoover Institution, Publications Department, 1965-1970 (Folder 11)
  - Iakovlev, A. V.
    - 1944-1950 (Folder 12)
    - 1951-1973 (Folder 13)
  - Institut zur Erforschung der UdSSSR. See below
  - Institute for the Study of the U. S. S. R. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - John Rylands Library, Manchester, 1944-1946 (Folder 2)
  - Journal of the American Association of Teachers of Slavic and East European Languages (AATSEEL Journal), 1954-1961 (Folder 3)
  - KPFA, 1959 (Folder 4)
  - Karpovich, Mikhail
    - 1951-1958 (Folder 5)
    - 1945-1958 (Folder 6)
  - Kasack, Wolfgang, 1980-1984 (Folder 7)
  - Kemball, Robin, 1957-1982 (Folder 8)
  - Kiparskii, Valentin, 1964 (Folder 9)
  - Kholodovskii, Evgenii, 1918 (Folder 10)
  - Korvin-Piotrowski, V. L., 1956-1967 (Folder 11)
  - Krikorian, Sergei, 1967-1982 (Folder 12)
  - Krivoshein, Kirill, 1974-1977 (Folder 13)
  - Kulik, Ivan, 1972 (Folder 14)
  - Kutyrina, Iulia, 1933-1963 (Folder 15)
  - Landau, Grigorii, 1929-1933 (Folder 16)
  - Lane, Olga and Roy, 1939-1977 (Folder 17)
  - Lange, Aleksandr, 1923-1925 (Folder 18)
  - Lasky, E., 1959 (Folder 19)
  - Lavrin, Janko, 1947-1964 (Folder 20)
  - Lee, Mollie, 1935-1966 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Leontiev, Leonid. See L'vov, Lollii
  - Levine, Isaac Don, 1966-1968 (Folder 2)
  - Lilliput, Pocket Publications Ltd., 1945-1948 (Folder 3)
  - Ljunggren, Magnus, 1973-1984 (Folder 4)
  - Lopatto, Michele, 1969-1980 (Folder 5)
  - Lossky, Nikolai, 1950-1961 (Folder 6)
  - Lountz, Gregory
    - 1946-1956 (Folder 7)
    - 1957-1967 (Folder 8)
    - 1968-1975 (Folder 9)
  - Lourie, Arthur, 1963-1964 (Folder 10)
  - L'vov, Lollii, 1924-1956 (Folder 11)
  - Maklakov, Vasilii, 1948-1952 (Folder 12)
  - Makovskii, Sergei, 1950-1960 (Folder 13)
  - Malia, Martin, 1955-1967 (Folder 14)
  - Mallac, Guy de, 1954-1981 (Folder 15)
  - Malmstad, John, 1970 (Folder 16)
  - Marchenko, Nikolai. See Morshen, Nikolai
  - Marie, Jean-Jacques. See Forgues, Pierre
  - Max Pfeffer Literary Agency, 1949 (Folder 17)
  - Mc Vay, Gordon, 1971-1983 (Folder 18)
  - Mel'gunov, Sergei, 1945-1953 (Folder 19)
  - Methuen & Co. Ltd., 1949-1965 (Folder 20)
  - Metzel, Boris, 1945-1946 (Folder 21)
  - Meyendorff, A., 1940-1957 (Folder 22)
  - Modern Language Association of America, 1954-1982 (Folder 23)
  - Mogilat, Elena, 1946-1980 (Folder 24)
  - Mois, 1931-1932 (Folder 25)
  - Muggeridge, Malcolm, 1934-1970 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - National Translation Center, 1967-1968 (Folder 2)
  - Naumann, Marina, 1974-1981 (Folder 3)
  - New Catholic Encyclopedia, 1963 (Folder 4)
  - New Leader
    - 1949-1958 (Folder 5)
    - 1959-1966 (Folder 6)
  - New Republic, 1963-1964 (Folder 7)
  - Nilson, Nils Ake, 1963-1966 (Folder 8)
  - Nordland Publishing Co., 1972-1976 (Folder 9)
  - Novoye Russkoye Slovo, 1947-1983 (Folder 10)
  - Novosel'e, 1947 (Folder 11)
  - The Oxford University Press, 1933-1977 (Folder 12)